# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
In today's video I'll share with you a homemade dish.
# 酱油泡青椒
Sauce pickled green chili peppers.
# 首先我们准备大青椒3个
First we prepare 3 green chili peppers.
# 去掉辣椒蒂之后从中间横竖各切1刀
Remove the stalk and cut twice into the pepper like a cross.
# 同学们为保证辣椒的完整性可以不用切断
You can leave the end connected to keep the nice shape of a pepper.
# 准备大红椒1个同样处理
Do the same for the one red pepper.
# 加大红椒除了增加成菜的甜味还能配色
Adding the red pepper is to bring some sweetness and color to the dish.
# 最后准备几个二荆条从中间切开备用
Finally have some "Erjingtiao" chili pepper cut from the middle.
# 不能吃辣的同学可以不加
You can skip it if you can't eat spicy food.
# 准备嫩仔姜1大块切成姜片备用
Slice a large chunk of young ginger into pieces.
# 准备大蒜几颗切成蒜片备用
And cut some cloves of garlic into pieces.
# 最后准备几根小葱头拍散之后切成葱段备用
Finally have some green onion root crushed and cut into smaller cylindrical pieces.
# 下一步开始腌制
Next to marinate the peppers,
# 盆中加入食用盐1大勺（约4克）
add 1 spoonful of salt (about 4g),
# 再加入1小把白糖（约30克）
and a small handful of white sugar (about 30g).
# 然后搅拌均匀腌制2小时备用
Then mix well and marinate for 2 hours.
# 这一步的目的是去除辣椒和辅料的生辣味
This step is to remove the strong spiciness from the peppers and other ingredients.
# 下一步开始准备料汁
Next we prepare the sauce.
# 碗中加入适量的青花椒
Add some Sichuan green peppercorn to a bowl,
# 加入八角1颗
and 1 piece of star anise.
# 再准备一个大盆
Then get a large bowl.
# 盆中加入保宁醋25克
Add 25g of "Baoning" vinegar in it.
# 加入生抽酱油350克
And 350g of soy sauce.
# 加入纯净水600克
Pour in 600g of pure water.
# 然后加入适量的食用盐搅拌均匀备用（约10克）
Then add some salt (about 10g) and mix well.
# 下一步开始熬汁
Next up to simmer the sauce.
# 首先我们直接将调好的料汁下锅
First we pour the prepared sauce into the wok.
# 然后开大火烧开之后倒出备用
Bring up the high heat and pour out the sauce once it boils.
# 这一步的目的是初步灭菌
This step is to pasteurize the sauce.
# 大火烧开之后锅离火再加入蚝油25克
When it comes to a boil, remove from heat and add 25g of eel sauce.
# 同学们蚝油可以不用加热
We don't need to heat the eel sauce.
# 这样才能够保留蚝油的原始鲜味
Because we want to keep the original umami taste in it.
# 将蚝油搅拌均匀之后倒出备用
After mixing the eel sauce well, transfer the sauce to a bowl for later use.
# 然后我们再次把锅烧热
Now we heat up the wok again.
# 锅烧热之后加入少许的底油
Then we add a little bit of base oil.
# 油温5成热之后将准备好的香料下锅
Add the spices when the temperature is about 150 °C.
# 然后转慢火炒香即可
Then turn to low heat and wait until you smell the aroma.
# 同学们酱油必须冷却之后才能够浸泡青椒
We must wait until the sauce is completely cooled down before soaking the peppers.
# 2个小时之后将腌制好的辣椒攥干水份备用
Two hours later dry the peppers by gripping on your hand.
# 然后将冷却的酱油搅拌均匀之后倒入装辣椒的盆中
Then pour the cooled sauce into the bowl containing peppers.
# 最后再浸泡腌制4小时即可食用
Finally pickle for 4 hours and the dish is ready.
# 一道非常美味爽口的酱油泡青椒就制作完成
A dish of very delicious and crisp soy sauce pickled green chili peppers is finished.
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，辣椒的种类可以根据个人口味选择
# 第二，腌制辣椒可以少加盐多加糖，这样可以中和辣椒的辣味
# 第三，腌制好的辣椒可以不必清洗直接攥干水份即可
# 第四，此菜非常适合作为早餐下白粥
# 第五，剩余的酱油可以反复使用2次左右
# 酱油泡青椒的技术总结完毕
Now the technical tips:
First, you can choose peppers according to you favor.
Second, peppers' spicy flavor can be neutralized by adding more sugar and less salt during the marination process.
Third, it's not necessary to wash the peppers after marination. Hand-drying is enough.
Fourth, this appetizer is an ideal side dish for eating rice porridge at breakfast.
Fifth, the remaining soy sauce can be reused about two more times.
That's all for the tips.